John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Corporate Structure, RG 1 FA1793
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Trustees, 1950-2019; 1; 33.99 Cubic Feet 87 letter document boxes and 5 half-letter boxes
  - Committees, 1950-2019; 3; 18.42 Cubic Feet 47 letter document boxes and 3 half-letter boxes
    - Planning and Program Commitee, 1950-2019; 12
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 September 16 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        Includes minutes of the June meeting and an agenda. Included are grant proposals, grant reports, program updates and memos on initiatives re: using journalists to report on Knight's learning; Community Foundations Initiative; and the Miami Arts Initiative.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2007 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        Includes minutes of the September meeting and an agenda; grant proposals; memos re: Miami Arts Initiative, and Ashoka fellowships, Communities Program (includes mention of Maidenberg retirement and hiring of Trabian Shorters) and Journalism Program Quarterly Reports; and proposed grant payout targets.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 March 10 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        Includes minutes of the December meeting and an agenda, grant proposals, the National and New Initiatives Program and Journalism Program Quarterly Reports; and proposed grant payout targets. Also included are memos re: Knight News Challenge - Year Two Updates; revised payout tracking report; and grant discussion memo.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        Includes minutes of the March meeting and an agenda; staff recommended grant proposals for communities, immigration, strategic, and journalism programs; quarterly program reports from Communities, the National and New Initiatives Program and Journalism Program; and grant reports, including grant payout commitments, and summaries of proposals recommended for approval or rejection, and grants approved by President. Also includes a memo from Alberto Ibarguen to the Trustees re: proposed community foundation initiative. Also included is a presentation to the Board on the Soul of the Community by Gallup Consulting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 September 14 (Box 7, Folder 1)
        Includes minutes of the June meeting and an agenda; staff recommended grant proposals for communities and journalism programs; quarterly program report from the National and Strategic Initiatives Program; and grant reports, including grant payout commitments, and summaries of proposals recommended for approval or rejection, and grants approved by President. Also includes a memo from Alberto Ibarguen to the Program Committee re: proposed South Florida Regional public broadcasting operation, trustee comments on proposed grants, and a memo from Lorenzo Lebrija, Miami Program Director re: Knight Arts Partnership Grant Recommendations.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2008 December 8 (Box 7, Folder 2)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the September meeting; grants budget; grant write-ups for the communities program, transformation fund, and journalism program; program quarterly reports; and summaries of approved and rejected grants.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 March 9 (Box 7, Folder 3)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the December meeting; proposed grants, including the Knight News Challenge, Knight Drupal Initiative, and Universal Access; grants budget update; program quarterly reports; and summaries of approved and rejected grants. Also included are minutes of the March meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 June 8 (Box 7, Folder 4)
        Committee materials include an agenda, March meeting minutes, information re: community engagement, investigative reporting initiative, KCIC, grants budget update, Teach for America and Program reports.Minutes of the June meeting; also included is a summary of grants; an update on the Gallup Poll on the Soul of the Community, Communities Overview, dated May 27, 2009; and charts on grant payout targets for 2009.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 September 14 (Box 7, Folder 5)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the June meeting; proposed grants under the following categories: Creative Corridor, Job Growth and Workforce Innovation, Digital Opportunity Challenge, Libraries, United States Artists, Charlotte Center for Urban Ministries and National Public Radio; grants budget update; program quarterly reports; and summaries of approved and rejected grants. Also included is minutes of the September meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2009 December 7 (Box 7, Folder 6)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the September meeting; memos re: Library Initiative, Knight Community Information Challenge, journalism grants, Knight News Testing Labs, and 2009 Grant Payout Update and Discussion; program reports; and summary of grants recommended for approval, approved and rejected. Includes a memo by Trabian Shorters re: Serious Games used to solve community problems. Also includes minutes of the meeting, and a Board presentation: "A Study of Community Leaders on the Impact of the Knight Foundation in 26 communities" by Bendixen and Associates.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 15 (Box 7, Folder 7)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the December and March meetings; memos re: Haitian issues in South Florida; Social Impact Games; Libraries Initiative; Florida Public Broadcasting Service; the proposed Knight News Testing Labs (includes report from Vince Stehle); charts of grant payouts for 2009 and 2010; reports from the program staff; and a summary of proposals recommended for approval.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 June 14 (Box 7, Folder 8)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the March meeting; memos re: Knight News Challenge grants; grant write-ups; chart of Knight Community Information Challenge Round III grant recommendations and grant write-ups; charts of KF's grant status as of 5/21/2010 and grant commitments 2004-2009; quarterly reports; and trustee comments. Also included are minutes of the June meeting with attachments re: Knight News Challenge winners and the Knight Community Information Challenge grantees.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 13 (Box 8, Folder 1)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the June meeting; memos re: Community Builders and LISC; African American Males Initiative; Knight Arts challenges in Miami and Philadelphia; the Ohr-O'Keefe Museum of Art in Biloxi; Journalism Education and Investigative Reporting Initiatives; Community Foundations; and reports re: 2010 payout updates, program quarterly reports; and summaries of proposals recommended for approval and of approvals and rejections. Also included are trustee comments and minutes of the September meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 13 (Box 8, Folder 2)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the September and December meetings; grant proposals re: ArtPlace, the Fund for Our Economic Future, the Bob Graham Center for Public Service, Women of Tomorrow, Living Cities, Mozilla Foundation, Northwestern University, The Bay Area News Citizen and the Centre County Community Foundation. Also included are memos on the 2010/2011 budgets, program quarterly reports, and grant proposals recommended for approval and rejected.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 3)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the December meeting; strategic assessment portfolio summaries - a compilation of summary descriptions of grant assessments and research projects concluded during the past quarter; grant initiatives re: Media Innovation Initiative at MIT, Engaged Communities, including the Central Corridor Funders Collaborative, Mobilize.org and Fostering the Arts with the Knight Arts Challenge; quarterly program reports; 2011 payout updates and a summary of proposals recommended for approval and rejection.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 June 13 (Box 8, Folder 4)
        Includes agenda, minutes of the March meeting; grant memos and write-ups on initiatives such as News21 at Arizona State University, the Knight News Challenge, Akron Neighborhood Trust, 1stAct Silicon Valley, World Wide Workshop for Children's Media Technology and Learning, Knight Community Infomation Challenge, Naturalization initiative, Libraries, Technology for Community Engagement and portfolio summaries and program quarterly reports. Also included is the minutes of the June meeting, with attachments.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 September 11 (Box 8, Folder 5)
        Agenda; committee materials, including June minutes, strategic assessment report, a review of findings from grant assessments and research projects, comments from trustees and staff reponses; grant write-ups; staff memos re: Knight Arts Challenge/Miami, Knight First Amendment Center status, and grant payouts; program quarterly reports; and September minutes. Also included is a memo re: redesign of grant write-up form.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2011 December 11 (Box 8, Folder 6)
        Agenda; September minutes; assessment and learning memos; grant write-ups; payout budget; and quarterly reports. Also included are staff responses to trustee comments and questions and minutes of the December meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2012 March 12 (Box 9, Folder 1)
        Agenda; December and March minutes; assessment and learning memos re: University of Miami, Knight Center for International Media, Center for Investigative Reporting, California Watch, Knight Community Information Challenge, Knight Arts Challenge, Miami and Real Time Charitable Giving, Text for Haiti Campaign; journalism project summaries; Knight Arts Challenge/Philadelphia recommendations; communities project summaries; transformation project summaries; payout budget; and quarterly reports. Also included are staff responses to trustee comments and questions.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2012 June 11 (Box 9, Folder 2)
        Agenda; March minutes; assessment and learning memos re: Social Impact Games, Knight News Challenge, Fund for Our Economic Future, and Black Male Engagement; journalism project summaries re: ProPublica, Knight News Challenge and Kickstarter; Informed and engaged communities re: Knight Community Information Challenge, Project LIFT and Aspen Institute; tech for Engagement re: CEOs for cities; Arts reP Knight Art Challenge Detroit and reports, including payout budget; and quarterly reports. Also included are staff responses to trustee comments and questions.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2012 September 10 (Box 9, Folder 3)
        Agenda; June minutes; assessment and learning memos re: College Hill Alliance, University Park Alliance, YouthBuild, and O, Miami; Arts re: Knight Arts Challenge Miami and Detroit; Informed and Engaged Communities re: Innovation Corridor, Urban Apps and Maps Studio, Connect 2 Compete, Open Knowledge Commons and Gathering of Leaders;Journalism and Media Innovation re: International Center for Journalists and Knight News Challenge; quarterly reports; endowment summary and summary of proposals recommended for approval or rejected.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2012 December 10 (Box 9, Folder 4)
        Agenda; September minutes; assessment and learning memos re: Public Insight Network, National Freedom of Information Coalition, Civic Commons; Tech for Engagement grants; Journalism and Media Innovation grants; Informed and Engaged Communities grants; quarterly reports; summary of proposals recommended for approval or rejected; and project summaries. Also inclued are December minutes.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2013 March 18 (Box 9, Folder 5)
        Agenda; December minutes; assessment and learning memos re: KCIC update and case studies, Community Foundation Giving Day Pilot Review; Tech for Engagement grants re: TurboVote and Youthbuild; Journalism and Media Innovation grants re: NPR, Aspen Institute, Texas Tribune, and Internet Archive; Informed and Engaged Communities re: Civic Commons; Arts re: KAC Philadelphia, Akron Art Museum and Arts Place; quarterly reports; 2013 payout update; summary of proposals recommended for approval, approvals and rejections; and project summaries. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2013 June 10 (Box 9, Folder 6)
        Minutes of the June meeting includes presentation of several new grants and initiatives. Included are summaries of proposals recommended for approval, approved by the President, and inquiries and rejections by staff. Presentation materials are: agenda; minutes of the March meeting; strategic assessment portfolio summaries for Q2/2013, which provides a review of findings from grant assessments and research projects; memos re: KF Giving Day Initiative, BMe Network, and New Economy Initiative; grant summaries for Project Liberty, Knight News Challenge Open Government; quarterly reports; and project summaries. Also included are two reports, "Why Contests Improve Philanthropy: Six Lessons on Designing Public Prizes for Impact" written by Mayur Patel, May 2013 and "Knight News Challenge: 2010 Winners Interim Report, March 2013.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2013 September 8 (Box 9, Folder 7)
        Agenda; Minutes of the June 2013 meeting; strategic assessment portfolio summaries for Q3; summary of KF's support for Digital Access, 2005-2012 by Mayur Patel and George Martinez, with an appendix of supplemental materials; Knight Community Information Challenge grant recommendations; grant summaries; quarterly reports; summary of proposals recommended for approval, approved by the President, and inquiries/rejections by staff. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2013 December 9 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Agenda; Minutes of the September 2013 meeting; Assessment and Learning: portfolio summaries; Communities: Studies and Convenings, LISC, and the St. Paul Foundation neighborhood challenge; update on Knight Community Information Challenge; Journalism and Media Innovation: local online media initiative, Knight News Challenge on Health, Pew Digital Research Partnership and University of Michigan/Livingston Awards; Arts: North Carolina Dance Theatre; and Quarterly Reports. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2014 March 17 (Box 10, Folder 2)
        Agenda; Minutes of the December 2013 meeting; Assessment and Learning; Communities; Journalism and Media Innovation; Arts and Reports re: 2014 payout updates, quarterly reports, summaries of proposals recommended for approval and for rejection; and project summaries. The new Prototype Fund; winners of the Knight News Challenge: Health; and the Detroit Institute of Arts fund were discussed. Also included are minutes of the March meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2014 June 9 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        Agenda; Minutes of the March 2014 meeting; Assessment and Learning - KNC evaluation of 2011 winners, Teach for America report, and Research on Talent Recruitment and Retention (Young and the Restless report); Informed and Engaged Communities - discussion of 7 grants; Journalism and Media Innovation - Mozilla, NY Times, Washington Post Commenting Platform, Document Cloud, MIT and KNC update; Arts - Inside/Out Initiative; Reports - 2014 payout update, quarterly reports, summary of proposals recommended for approval, approvals and rejections; Supporting Materials, including KNC proposed winners.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2014 September 7 (Box 11, Folder 1)
        Agenda; Minutes of the June 2014 meeting; summary of proposals recommended for approval, approved by the President and declined; program quarterly reports; strategy and assessment one-page summaries for the Future of the First Amendment survey and the Giving Day initiative; memo from Carol Coletta re: request for funding of Knight Cities Challenge; grant write-ups; Knight Arts Challenge Miami, Detroit and St. Paul recommended winners for 2014; Q3 2014 Grant Payout Update. Supplemental materials include full reports from Assessment and Learning re: Future of the First Amendment and Giving Day Initiative Review; and grant project summaries.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2014 December 8 (Box 11, Folder 2)
        Agenda; Minutes of the September 2014 meeting; summary of proposals recommended for approval, approved by the President and declined; program quarterly reports; and Q4 and 2015 grant payout discussions. Also includes minutes of the December meeting, with attachments.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2015 March (Box 11, Folder 3)
        Agenda; Minutes of the December 2014 meeting; summary of proposals and project summaries for grants recommended for approval, approved by the President and declined; program quarterly reports; strategy and assessment; and 2015 grant payout discussions. Also includes minutes of the December meeting, with attachments and a draft of a Pew Research Center report, "Local News in the Digital Age". Also included are March meeting minutes.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2015 June (Box 11, Folder 4)
        Agenda; Minutes of the March meeting; summary of proposals and project summaries for grants recommended for approval, approved by the President and declined; program quarterly reports; strategy and assessment; and 2015 grant payout discussions. Also included are a draft of a report by Lake Research Partners re: Local Voting Drop-Off Research; and Gaining Ground: How Nonprofit News Ventures Seek Sustainability (April 2015). Also included are minutes and amended minutes of the June meeting. The minutes were amended to reflect the recusal of several trustees from voting of grants for which they had an interest.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2015 September (Box 11, Folder 5)
        Agenda; memo from Terese Coudreaut re: livestreaming of the Program Committee and Open session of the Board meeting to Knight Central; June minutes; program quarterly reports; grants for discussion; 2015 Payout Update; summary of proposals recommended for approval and summary of approvals and rejections. Supplemental materials include full assessment of Media Accelerators and project summaries for four Journalism and two CNI grants. A list of Knight Arts Challenge recommended winners is also included. Also included are September minutes.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2015 December 7 (Box 12, Folder 1)
        Agenda; September minutes; program quarterly reports; grants for discussion; 2015 Payout Update; summary of proposals recommended for approval and summary of approvals and rejections. Supplemental materials include Learning and Impact reports re: Understanding News Behavior on Mobile Devices, draft prepared by Nielsen; Virtual Reality and Immersive Storytelling; and Catalyzing Connections: Miami's Startup Ecosystem (early version); and full information on the proposed grants.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2016 March 7 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        Memo from Terese Coudreaut re: dry run presentations and agenda. Program Committee book, which includes agenda; December 2015 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups, and a 2016 payout update. Also included are minutes of the meeting.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2016 June 13 (Box 12, Folder 3)
        Program Committee book, which includes agenda; March 2016 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; and a 2016 payout update.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2016 September 12 (Box 12, Folder 4)
        Program Committee book, which includes agenda; June 2016 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; and a 2016 payout update. Also included is a copy of the 2016 Strategic Plan, Learning and Impact portfolio summaries for Q3-2016. Appendix materials include memo seeking a two year extension for the Knight Community Information Challenge; Future of the First Amendment 2016 Survey of High School Students and Teachers (draft); a Gallup survey, "Free Expression on Campus: A Survey of U.S. College Students and U.S. Adults; survey report: In Defense of the First Amendment; Table Stakes Project Interim Summary; Beyond the dollars: The long-term value of giving days for community foundations; Innovation in the Public Media System: A Review of recent Knight Foundation grants; and Podcasting and On-Demand Audio: A review of recent Knight Foundation investments and Lessons from the field.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2016 December (Box 12, Folder 5)
        Program Committee book, which includes agenda; September 2016 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; and a 2016 payout update. Also included is a Learning and Impact Q4-2016 portfolio summaries; and Museum Tech Initiative and Exploration of Literacy updates. Appendix materials include reports re: Detroit Development Fund Evaluation, Youth News ad Media Habits Study, Mozilla OpenNews Evaluation, Knight Arts Challenge Evaluation, Detroit Journalism Cooperative and Knight Cities Challenge Update.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2017 March 6 (Box 12, Folder 6)
        Program Committee book, which includes agenda; December 2016 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; Also included is Q1-2017 Grant Payout Update; Knight Cities Challenge proposed winners; and Art Museum Tech Initiative. Appendix materials include reports re: Knight Cities Challenge Evaluation; Diverse Asset Managers Research; and Role of Information and Tech in a Democracy.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2017 June 12 (Box 12, Folder 7)
        Program Committee book, which includes agenda; March 2017 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; Also included is Q2-2017 Grant Payout Update; Strategy and Impact Review Knight Initiative on Trust, Media, and Democracy; Also included is the Dry Run Meeting book of the Program Committee.
      - Meeting Minutes - signed, 2017 June 12 (Box 12, Folder 8)
        Signed minutes from the Program Committee Meeting on June 12, 2017. Includes Attachment A, summary of recommended proposals; Attachment B, grants approved by president and declined grants statistics
      - Meeting Minutes, 2017 September 10 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        Minutes with Attachment A-B and materials for Program Committee meeting on September 10, 2017. Includes June 2017 minutes; quarterly reports; grant write-ups; Also included is Q3-2017 Grant Payout Update; Program-by-Program Strategy and Impact Review: Draft of Technology Innovation; CNI Draft Five-Year Statements of Strategy, an internal draft to the Knight BOT on sustaining civic tech-seeding and scaling civic startups; Also included are the Knight Arts Challenge Winners; List of commissioners for Knight Commission on Trust, Media and Democracy.
      - Meeting Minutes, 2017 December 11 (Box 12, Folder 10)
        Minutes with Attachment A-B and Program Committee materials for December 11, 2017; agenda; minutes from September 2017 meeting; quarterly reports; The Future of Journalism, 10-year review; The Future of Arts in Miami; Learning and Impact, How Americans Navigate the News Landscape; Community and National Initiatives; Journalism
      - Meeting Minutes, 2018 March 12 (Box 13, Folder 1)
        Minutes with Attachments A-B and materials for the Program Committee Meeting on March 12, 2018; minutes from December 2017 meeting; Learning and Impact, Free Expression on Campus, Detroit Development Fund; Community and National Initiatives, Toward a Knight Smart Cities Strategy, grants to approve; Arts grants to approve; Journalism grants to approve
      - Meeting Minutes, 2018 June 11 (Box 13, Folder 2)
        Minutes with Attachments A-B and materials for the meeting of the Program Committee on June 11, 2018. Minutes from Program Committee Meeting in March 2018; Quarterly Reports, Technology in the Knight Program; Learning and Impact, Understanding attitudes about trust accuracy and bias - Gallup Research, initiatives to approve; Arts, Evolving arts ecosystems in Detroit and Miami, grants and initiatives to approve; Community and National Initiatives, Knight Community Profiles, Miami Strategy Update and Discussion, grants and initiatives to approve. Program Committee Appendix includes full reports
      - Meeting Minutes, 2018 September 16 (Box 13, Folder 3)